<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your awesome title</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 16:34:48 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 16:34:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Preparing for Escape</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a miscellaneous collection of what I’ve been up to these past two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;periodic-table&quot;&gt;Periodic table&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We couldn’t find an adequate periodic table online or on Amazon, so I ended up modifying one I found that was in HTML and CSS form. What we needed was a periodic table without any extraneous numbers, but also included the full names of the elements so that the puzzles we constructed could be solved. I ended up making &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/themichaelyang/pen/bJQVbG&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, and we printed it out really big thanks to the in-browser PDF print exports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/periodic-table-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Custom periodic table.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Custom periodic table.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During playtesting, we ended up discovering that the colors were a bit misleading due to our glasses puzzle. I’m going to modify these colors so they aren’t visible from the red glasses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-app&quot;&gt;Web app&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a basic web interface for remotely activating some gamemastered elements of the game: changing Dr. Sanchez’s computer, and playing the time machine video. It works using Node.js and Socket.io, and is deployed to Heroku. The idea is that we will have Raspberry Pis running the web app, and our gamemastering computer running the controller interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/interface.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gamemaster web interface.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Gamemaster web interface.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What remains is constructing the time machine walls, the time machine control panel, and putting it all into the room with our A/V equipment. We’re also going to have to add a lot more props; the room feels very sparse as it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;raspberry-pi&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up the Raspberry Pis turned out to be quite a task. I dug up two Pis from as old as 2015, a Model B and an original Pi. Here’s a list of the issues I ended up running into:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forgot the password for the older Pi; luckily Pis are very insecure and you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://mapledyne.com/ideas/2015/8/4/reset-lost-admin-password-for-raspberry-pi&quot;&gt;easily reset it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Older Pi lacks wifi reciever since I lost it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boot from USB not setup on newer Pi; had to install OS on microSD to first boot in order to set this bit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pis play poorly with WPA2-Enterprise wifi authentication; default GUI wifi wouldn’t &lt;a href=&quot;http://lmgtfy.com/?q=eduroam+raspberry+pi&quot;&gt;allow me to connect to eduroam&lt;/a&gt; and I needed &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wpa_gui&lt;/code&gt; for this and it somehow worked (settings: WPA2-Enterprise, PEAP, standard logins). Default “nyu” wifi wouldn’t work, and didn’t even show up at all (I have no clue why; &lt;a href=&quot;https://itp.nyu.edu/classes/cdni-spring2015/how-to/itp-networks/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/raspberry_pi/comments/556nej/wpa2enterprise/&quot;&gt;are&lt;/a&gt; some potential clues)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pis also play poorly with the apostrophe (’) in iPhone hotspot names: Michael’s iPhone gave some weird character encoding errors, and I had to change my phone’s name to MyPhone in order to get this to work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The files for NOOBS and Raspbian were massive and took a long time to download&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Formatting the flash drive for Raspbian took forever as well (even longer than the download)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There was a chance the flash drive wouldn’t even be compatible with booting since I got it for free from a career fair, but I got lucky&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Running the initial install also took a long time (you can sense a pattern now)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/05/01/preparing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/05/01/preparing.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Puzzle Planning: Part II</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For today’s meeting, we finalized the puzzle design, including adjusting the story to fit the new plan. The finalized puzzle flow ended up being:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unlock time machine door (to activate machine)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repair time machine to travel back to present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also planned the exact puzzles and split up the prototype work. My task was building out the puzzle elements on the Dr’s computer, which would initially be one newspaper article. After the time travel section, the computer would change to be logged out, and require the players to call IT using the Dr’s phone to recover her password (using information in the Dr’s wallet that appears in her lab coat). After unlocking the computer, a second newspaper article would provide additional clues and story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the design of this puzzle was a desire to incorporate a “real world” interactive element. This is part of our longest subpuzzle sequence, and has yet to be tested, so it’ll be interesting to see if the puzzle succeeds in playtesting. One concern is that players might not understand that they can actually call with the phone they are given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/login-screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;Login screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prototype for this can be played &lt;a href=&quot;/part2.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The password is “hotdog”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/04/17/puzzle-planning-part-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/04/17/puzzle-planning-part-2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Puzzle Planning: Part I</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last class, we decided on an outline for the story and began brainstorming puzzles ideas. The story (subject to change) is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You are the research team of the famous Dr. Maria Sanchez, who has recently gone missing after refusing to turn over the findings of her latest secret project to some big evil tech company. She has left you with a series of cryptic instructions to recover the project. After rifling through her lab, you discover that she was silenced after discovering time travel, and you repair the machine to go back in time and save Dr. Sanchez!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story extends to a natural puzzle flow consisting of two “meta-puzzles”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activating the time machine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Saving Dr. Maria (escaping the room)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met as a group today to work out some of the details of the time machine and the first meta-puzzle. After looking at the room size, we decided on using the corner of the room immediately right of the entrance for our time machine. In order to simplify the space requirements and machine design, our time machine would consist of a curtain / folding door on a rail and a control panel box. This way the construction and setup of the time machine would be modular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the machine to work, we wanted to have the results of the sub-puzzles to include several “parts” that fit into the sides of the control panel box. Some ideas included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schematics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Date to travel to&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motherboard (magnets)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screw in part&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also considered having it wired up so the machine would automatically be able to detect when it was repaired and produce effects, time permitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/time-machine-plans.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Time machine and puzzle flow planning.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Time machine and puzzle flow planning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some ideas we had for puzzles included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mixing colors in beakers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using colored glasses to decipher a hidden password&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a periodic table to translate into a combination lock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online newspaper that changes after time travel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We began working on some really rough prototypes of these puzzles and set pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/time-machine-inspiration.png&quot; alt=&quot;Time machine inspiration.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Time machine inspiration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/04/10/puzzle-planning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/04/10/puzzle-planning.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Field Notes from Outer Space</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do an escape room: Take note of the design of the room.  What are the rules of the room? How do different players interact with the room and each other? What does the room and its objects look like?  What are the different types of puzzles? How is the game setup?  What is the role of the gamemaster?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/alien-attack.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Aliens got us!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday night (in a bit of a last minute booking), I went to Koreatown to play &lt;a href=&quot;https://nyc.escape-entertainment.com/&quot;&gt;Escape Entertainment’s&lt;/a&gt; “Alien Attack” escape room with my sister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t make it out alive, but had a fun time and came close despite being a small team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-setting&quot;&gt;The setting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The premise of the game was that we were aboard a Russian spaceship, and aliens are attacking. We were lead into a dimly lit room, with lots of metal paneling and flashing emergency lights (the spaceship), where we were explained the instructions (no puzzles require force, where the button for emergency exit, etc), and where we were provided smartphones preloaded with a couple very specific apps, the most unique part of the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a number of screens mounted around the room, including TVs and tablets. The TV at the front of the room displaying some control panel graphics, and a big button. The center of the room had a table, and there were 4 smaller connecting rooms acting as different parts the spaceship) which were initially locked behind sliding doors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the signage around the room was in Russian. Occasionally a siren would sound, or a Russian speaker would come over the loudspeaker. Towards the end of the game the frequency of these random sounds would increase and the lighting turned more red, giving a pretty strong sense of urgency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-game&quot;&gt;The game&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most compelling aspect of the game was the addition of smartphones preloaded with several apps, including a translation camera, an AR camera app, and a flashlight. Because everything was in Russian, it added an additional twist in deciphering a lot of the puzzles. The AR app also had us pointing the camera at everything for clues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without giving too much away, the games within the smaller rooms were generally a combination of physical/spatial puzzles (figuring out where things go) and then logical (figuring out how to use the completed puzzle to get a password).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because there were usually multiple puzzles needing to be solved at any time and the smartphone translation / AR, we naturally split up tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the game, the gamemaster would give us hints when we got stuck, which made a sound and showed up on the TV with the countdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;some-thoughts&quot;&gt;Some thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I definitely liked the inclusion of the apps a lot, but there definitely was some finicky parts with the translation not always working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do wish that the setting was stronger and the puzzles tied more directly to the setting. The sense of urgency didn’t really kick in until the end when the sirens and lights kept going off. The dimness, although cool initially, got in the way of the puzzles sometimes when we had to constantly hold a flashlight to read the signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gamemaster helped a lot with our pacing by giving us clear hints when we got totally stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was definitely the most technologically savvy escape room I’ve been in, with its use of apps, tablets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/04/04/field-notes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/04/04/field-notes.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
